Colin Birdwell FRONT END DEVELOPER

http://www.webbybirdwell.com https://github.com/C-Birdwell web.by.birdwell@gmail.com (713) 542-4597

SUMMARY

Colin has worked with online and digital businesses both as a web & app developer, in the industries of private agencies, online commerce, local government, utilities, and the financial banking. Bringing more than five years of experience, Colin can handle your front end coding needs.

As an App Developer, he built the front end of a personal banking debit card app while using a in house api to update the backend. Colin incorporated concepts of templated components, extensive visual animations, and haptic feedback.

As a Web Developer, his skills include working knowledge of several various web based languages, User Experience & User Interface design (UX/UI), online interactions, web design, and working within small, innovative teams of developers in an Agile/Scrum setting.

Colin also has extensive knowledge on IT operations, middleware experience, and some back-end experience with things like Node.js and SQL.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Payment Data Systems Inc / Usio Front end developer

San Antonio, Texas April 2018 - July 2019

Was main lead front end developer on rebuilding their proprietary financial debit card banking app white label template Akimbo onto a react-native platform.

App requirements included:

- Used React-Native for all front end
- Heavy use of Axios for http requests
- Animating visual components with haptic feedback
- Card to card transfers
- Bank to card transfers
- Scheduling recurring transfers (utilizing Moment.js to calculate future dates to pick from)
- Enrollment
- Image upload
- Maintaining a list of transaction history
- Ordering new debit cards, enrollment
- Using keychain to store secure login information & touch id biometrics
- Utilizing environmental files for on boarding clients to utilize their branding for templating purposes
- Displaying a live balance of each card

Also assisted and monitored digital art assets for maintaining consistent brand guidelines (consistent colors on sites, making sure fonts were consistent, using the same border radius on visual components, etc...).

San Antonio Water System Via Sistema Technologies

January 2017 - February 2018

The main project worked was a customer portal that handled water bill account needs.

- Coordinating responsive web development with project leads
- Advised on UX/UI related matters
- Integrated web technologies with legacy systems
- Experiential Design

Web Developer Consultant

Freelance Web Development Web Developer

January 2014 - Present

As a freelance web developer, I help smaller clients with a variety of web-related needs including:

- Site development
- Consulting, general website maintenance & troubleshooting, custom email templates
- Social media
- Google Apps integration
- A variety of other website/web-related needs

DeFalco's Home Wine and Beer Supplies

Houston, Texas June 2016 - September 2016

Web Developer and Consultant

With my experience as a developer:

- I supervised the implementation of a new website for the client's e-commerce needs
- Consulted about the possibilities of greater web presence
- Implementing SEO to establish data feed back targeted at existing and new customer bases

Signet Interactive Web Developer

September 2014 - June 2016

My primary role as a web developer at Signet Interactive, my duties included:

- Develop and create the functional websites
- Followed proper web standards, as well as the user experience for both mobile and desktop in mind

Advanced

Variety of web-related aspects, in regards to maintenance and support

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML Expert
CSS Expert
Javascript Expert
React Intermediate
React-Native Advanced

React-Native Advanced
Redux Intermediate
Axios Intermediate
Jquery Advanced
ModX Expert
Wordpress Intermediate

Node.js Intermediate Version Control Advanced UI/UX Advanced Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator Beginner Intermediate npm Gulp Intermediate PHP Beginner Beginner AJAX eCommerce Intermediate

Big Commerce Advanced
Bootstrap Expert
Flexbox Intermediate
CSS Grid Intermediate
Formstack Advanced
Social Media Integration Advanced

Google Analytics Intermediate
Campaign Monitor, MailChimp, etc., Custom Advanced

Email Template creation

Hubspot

Bitbucket
Github
Sourcetree
Yarn
Visual Studio
Git
Sass

GraphQL

Advanced
Advanced
Intermediate
Intermediate
Intermediate
Advanced
Beginner

EDUCATION

University of Houston Bachelor of Arts

Houston, Texas Graduated August 2009

LANGUAGES

English

Native

REFERENCES

Derek Lanphier

Former Manager

Signet Interactive / San Antonio Water System

2800 U.S. Hwy 281 North, San Antonio, Texas 78212

(281) 907-1460

derek.lanphier@saws.org

Sukari Schutzman

Co-Worker / Peer Small Dog Agency

3103 Eisenhauer Rd San Antonio, TX 78209

(916) 918-9369

sukari@smalldogagency.com

Roland Portillo

Co-Worker / Peer

San Antonio Water System

2800 U.S. Hwy 281 North, San Antonio, Texas 78212

(210) 872-9453

roland.portillo@saws.org